Our
next
[Music]
is president of the organization of
Chinese American
Cleveland. He's also the co of the
Cleveland
[Applause]
Hello. I'd like to take this opportunity
to congratulate all the
[Music]
was born in Cleveland, Ohio. She is an
educator and strong advocate for the
Japanese American
[Music]
community. Beverly is third generation
Japanese American. Both of her parents'
families were incarcerated in German
camps during World War
II. With the loss of their California
home and businesses, they resettled in
the area.
[Music]
While growing up in the Midwest after
the war, many Japanese American
presented unique
challenges. Consequently, Japanese
Americans for social clubs and
[Music]
organizations will serve as officer of
the Cleveland Jac which is the local
chapter of the Japanese American
Citizens League. It is the first and
oldest
Asian-American civil rights organization
in the United States.
She has organized workshops, advocated
civil rights, coordinated youth programs
and events for the Japanese
[Music]
American
dancers. They perform locally and all
over Iowa. They performed at Year
events, the African Superior Festival,
the Cleveland Nation Festival, and many,
many different events throughout
Ohio. She even taught Japanese to
Spider-Man and
friends just last night.
Last year played a key role in
restructuring the annual festival. It
upholds the traditions of our families
and
ancestors. She actively coordinated the
79th hospital uniting Japanese dancers
JCL and the Cleveland American
Foundation sponsors. This year marks the
80th hospital in Cleveland. It'll take
place on July
20th. Beverly has also served as the
president of CARA which is the Cleveland
Asian retired person's organization.
She's a member of the JCL scholarship
committee. Even though she's retired,
she continues her role as an educator
through dance work as a substitute
teacher and remains actively involved in
the community.
is truly one of Cleveland's most devoted
leaders in our multiculture
society. Always admire her for positive
attitude and gentle
leadership. It is my honor and privilege
to introduce the first person of
Japanese ancestry to receive the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame
award for a lifetime achievement in the
Japanese American community.
Early heat.
[Music]
Thank you for the lovely introduction,
Lisa. Congratulations to the 2025
inductees. My heartfelt thanks to Dan
Hansen and the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame. I share his
recognition with my colleagues. The
color is dancing
to table present and past
dancers presiding the Cleveland Japanese
Foundation are Bill and Taki.
music choice
and Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
My
polish is here
with Michael here with
Claire from your Jes.
Cleveland is great
because it welcomed the Japanese and
Japanese Americans out of the house when
they were
homeless. Our family have learned to
live and was followed by the Cleveland
community and um on February 19th,
1942, President Franklin D. Rose signing
executive order
9066. I would hope we would learn from
history. 120 men, women, and children of
Japanese and Japanese descent were put
in the camps in deserts in the parts of
the United
States. Twoth3 of those were American
citizens.
There were no incidents of criminal or
things against our government. In fact,
many of the men did serve as United
States
military. Now, when we settled in
Cleveland, first of all, my parents gave
me a name that no Japanese person can
pronounce.
There are no fees or if you for those of
you that are educators, you do have to
speak the language prior to the age of
seven brush.
Okay. So, dead
body was born in your home hospital in
Cleveland and as a child I was sent home
one day and they said I wanted to go
home and I was at my friend's house to
eat. What I said is I wanted
Gohan and my mother laughed. I never got
a meal. Gohan is the Japanese word for
right.
[Music]
So I gratefully accept this prestigious
award on behalf of the current and past
Japanese American community.